双语特效字幕
百度贴吧衣柜字幕组
专注GOT剧集 华语冰火最专业字幕
翻译 艾莉娅的缝衣针
翻译 为万世开百事
翻译   barossa
君临 King's Landing
翻译  FuriousFurion
红堡
Red Keep
校对 加文・维斯特林
赫伦堡 Harrenhal
校对 夏大猫子
奔流城 Riverrun
奔
流
城
Riverrun
奔
流
校对  临冬城的狮子
临冬城 Winterfell
监制  临冬城的狮子
后期 poplar 窝鹏偏逢连夜雪
策划  baozhenyuawabi
特别顾问 屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
绝境长城 the Wall
最专业的华语冰火资料站：冰与火之歌中文维基
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
百度冰与火之歌贴吧 & 百度权力的游戏贴吧  联合出品
阿斯塔波Astapor
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治・R・R・马丁
权力的游戏
第三季 第四集
衣柜字幕组
第四集  "And Now His Watch Is Ended"
至死方休
你觉得他的屁股里
How many of those fingers
詹姆・兰尼斯特
“弑君者” 御林铁卫队长
能塞进多少根儿手指啊？
do you think we could shove up his ass?
这可得看他之前有没有练习过
Depends if he's had any practice.
布蕾妮・塔斯
“美人” 詹姆的护卫
你跟你姐姐搞的时候玩过这种花样吗？ 弑君者？
Is that the sort of thing you and your sister go in for, Kingslayer?
洛克
她可曾替我们松过你的菊花？
She loosened you up for us?
他要摔下来了
He's going to fall.
他要从马上摔下来了 来人帮帮他啊
He's going to fall off his horse. Someone help him.
水
Water.
求求你 水
Please, water.
水 水
Wa-water.
水 求求你
Water, please.
求求你 求求你
Please. Please.
如果我死了 你就什么也――
If I die, you won't be getting--
哦 得了吧
Oh, enough.
给
Here.
还真没见过有人连喝马尿都喝的这么带劲呐
Can't say that I've ever seen a man drink horse piss that fast.
住手！
Stop!
够了
Far enough.
胆敢再犯 我就剁了你的另一只手
Do that again and I'll take your other hand.
你进来吧
Come on, you.
提利昂・兰尼斯特
“小恶魔” 财政大臣
哦 提利昂大人 进来 进来
Oh, Lord Tyrion. Come in, come in.
我希望咱俩能够
I hope we might speak.
推心置腹的谈一谈
In confidence.
哦 咱不一直都推心置腹的嘛
Oh, always in confidence.
关于黑水河的那档子事儿
About the events of the Blackwater.
现在谈这个是否有些不合时宜？
Perhaps this is the wrong time?
哦 不 我看正合时宜
Oh, no. It's a wonderful time.
我觉得没准你的某只小小鸟
I thought one of your little birds
知道点什么 关于我姐姐图谋……
might have knowledge of my sister's intentions to--
取您性命？
End your life?
虽然我接过了小指头的职位
I didn't inherit Littlefinger's spies
但他可没把那些耳目眼线一并留给我
along with his position, I'm afraid.
所以我只能来找你帮忙
Which is why I'm coming to you.
- 我需要证据 - 证据？
- I need proof. - Proof?
瓦里斯
“八爪蜘蛛” 情报总管
- 还会有审判么？ - 是我想知道而已
- Will there be a trial? - I need to know.
她曾对我密语 可我没有别的证据
I have no proof, only whispers.
在讨论这些见不得人的东西前
Before all this nastiness,
我本想跟你讲讲我是如何被阉的
I was going to tell you the story of how I was cut.
你现在还想听么？
Do you want to hear it still?
不知道 我该听么？
I don't know. Do I?
当我还是个男孩的时候 我曾跟着一个剧团
As a boy, I travelled with a troupe of actors
在自由城邦巡演
through the Free Cities.
有一天 在密尔
One day in Myr,
一个男人给我的主人开了一个
a certain man made my master an offer
无法拒绝的高价
too tempting to refuse.
我很害怕 担心这男人会怎样对我
I feared the man meant to use me as I'd heard
他会不会是那种对男童感兴趣的人
some men used small boys.
然而事实比这更糟
But what he wanted was far worse.
他对我下了药
He gave me a potion
那药水让我无法动弹 甚至无法言语
that made me powerless to move or speak,
可它却没有麻痹我的感觉
yet did nothing to dull my senses.
他用一柄弯刀 将我的那里连根带梢
With a hooked blade he sliced me,
一片一片的切下 然后他伴着咒语
root and stem, chanting all the while.
将它们丢入火盆中烧掉
He burned my parts in a brazier.
火焰转而变蓝
The flames turned blue
然后我听到有个声音响应了他的召唤
and I heard a voice answer his call.
如今我仍会时不时的梦到它――
I still dream of that night.
梦到的不是那个巫师
Not of the sorcerer,
也不是那把刀
not of his blade.
而是那个火焰里的声音
I dream of the voice from the flames.
那是个神祗？ 还是恶魔？
Was it a god? A demon?
又或是魔术师的鬼把戏？
A conjuror's trick?
我不知道
I don't know.
但是确实有个声音响应了巫师的召唤
But the sorcerer called and a voice answered.
从那天起
And ever since that day,
我开始憎恨一切魔法 和使用它们的人
I have hated magic and all those who practice it.
这就是为什么我要如此热切的帮助你
But you can see why I was eager to aid
对抗史坦尼斯和他的红袍女祭司
in your fight against Stannis and his Red Priestess.
这算是某种复仇的象征
A symbolic revenge of sorts.
是的 嗯… 我急不可耐地要跟那些
Yes, ahem. I feel the need for actual revenge
想置我于死地的人来一场
against the actual person
真刀真枪的复仇
who tried to have me killed.
但是这事儿没点影响力可办不到 而这些……
Which will require a degree of influence, which--
恰是你此时此刻
You do not possess
所不具备的
at the moment.
说到影响力 我发现这玩意儿
But influence is largely
实际上就是耐性的较量
a matter of patience, I have found.
那巫师利用完我以后
Once I had served the sorcerer's purpose,
便把我丢出门外 让我自生自灭
he threw me out of his house to die.
可我恨他
I resolved to live
我偏要活下去
to spite him.
我不惜乞讨
I begged.
不惜出卖自己剩下的那部分身体
I sold what parts of my body remained to me.
直到我变成了一个颇有手段的窃贼
I became an excellent thief
很快 我发现 一个人信里的东西
and soon learned that the contents of a man's letters
往往比他钱包里的更值钱
are more valuable than the contents of his purse.
于是我一步一步忍着
Step by step,
忍着完成一个又一个令人恶心的任务
one distasteful task after another,
终于我爬出了密尔的贫民窟
I made my way from the slums of Myr
坐到了御前议会的桌前
to the small council chamber.
影响力如同野草 火烧不尽 风吹又生
Influence grows like a weed.
我以耐心灌溉之
I tended mine patiently
才使其能绵延繁茂如今 从红堡檐下
until its tendrils reached from the Red Keep
一路不绝 爬到世界的尽头
all the way across to the far side of the world
所以我才能够在这野草之下 藏得住那些……
where I managed to wrap them around something
特别的东西
very special.
那个巫师
The sorcerer.
你好啊 老朋友
Hello, my old friend.
好久不见啊
It's been a long time.
我坚信 相报有时 而你的仇
I have no doubt the revenge you want
终将得偿……
will be yours in time...
只要你念念不忘 耐心等待
if you have the stomach for it.
从来没听说过
When people talk about the Night's Watch,
葛兰
守夜人游骑兵
守夜人还要铲土的……
they never mention the shoveling.
还有这些臭屎
Or the shit.
它们总是拿什么荣誉 赦免来说事儿
They tell you about honor, pardoning crimes,
还有保卫王国
and protecting the realm,
但其实铲土才是最主要的部分吧
but shoveling really is most of it.
还有遇袭 被杀 甚至更糟
And getting attacked or killed or worse.
诸如此类 当没有遇袭 被杀的时候
And that. But when you're not getting attacked or killed,
基本上都在铲土
usually you're shoveling.
哦 快看
Oh, look.
更多的屎
More shit.
艾迪森・托勒特
“忧郁的艾迪” 守夜人事务官
我在想今天剩下的时间
I was starting to wonder what to do
要做些什么了
with the rest of my day.
我们得离开这儿
We need to get out of here.
当司令官大人说走的时候 我们才能走
When the Lord Commander says we go, we go.
司令官大人曾让我们去先民拳峰
The Lord Commander told us to go to the Fist of the First Men.
- 结果呢？ - 可是他也不知道会变成这样啊
- How'd that turn out for us? - He had no way of knowing.
现在我们知道了
We do now.
我们知道那有些什么玩意儿了
We know what's out there.
卡斯特在这儿都能生存下来
Craster's been out here surviving.
雷斯特
守夜人
所以他现在成了你的新任监护人了？
So he's your new protector now?
我们的好朋友卡斯特？
Our good friend Craster?
我们就跟他那些丢掉的儿子一样
We're like the sons he never had.
莫尔蒙救不了你
Mormont isn't gonna save you.
这些蠢货也救不了你
This lummox here isn't gonna save you.
只要异鬼一句话
When the walkers come calling,
卡斯特立刻就会把咱们当猪一样献祭出去
Craster will serve us up like so many pigs.
如果我们还想要命……
If we want to live...
我们就得为自己打算
we'll have to look out for ourselves.
吉莉
卡斯特的女儿与妻子
嘘 嘘 嘘
Shh, shh, shh.
- 你吵醒他了 - 对不起
- You woke him. - I'm sorry.
山姆威尔・塔利
守夜人事务官
- 他真美 - 嘘
- He's beautiful. - Shh!
他真美
He's beautiful.
他有名字么？
Does he have a name?
- 没有 - 你要给他起名吗？
- No. - Are you going to give him one?
为什么？
Why?
给
Here.
吉莉
Gilly.
你说在你回来之前 让我替你保管它
You said to hold it for you until you came back.
- 你现在回来了 - 我希望你能留着它
- You're back. - I wanted you to have it.
我才不想要这傻乎乎的顶针
I don't want your stupid thimble.
我想要救我孩子的命 你能做到吗？
I want to save my baby's life. Can you do that?
能吗？
Can you?
我没空搭理你
I don't have time for you.
除了他 我没空搭理任何人
I don't have time for anyone but him
因为他没多少时间了
because he doesn't have much time.
你得去找他
You have to go after him.
怎么找？
How?
布兰・史塔克
你知道该怎么找
You know how.
布兰登
Brandon.
妈妈
Mother.
我跟你说过多少次了
How many times have I told you?
- 不要攀爬 - 妈妈 我得找到它
- No climbing. - Mother, I need to find it.
- 它就在这儿 它在召唤我 - 你得向我保证
- It's here. It's calling me. - I want you to promise me.
凯特琳・徒利
艾德・史塔克的遗孀
别再爬了 答应我
No more climbing. Promise me.
答应我！ 答应我！
Promise me! Promise me!
-妈妈！妈妈！ -答应我！答应我 布兰！
- Mother! Mother! - Promise me! Promise me, Bran!
答应我！
Promise me!
玖健・黎德
他那活儿很大？
Is he very large?
看起来也没大多少
No larger than usual, apparently.
- 不过她们说他…… - 不同寻常
- And yet they said that he was-- - Extraordinary.
她们所见过的最特别的男人
The most extraordinary man they've ever had.
萝丝
妓女
她们可是阅人无数
And they've had a lot of men.
我们说的是同一个波德瑞克吗？
We're talking about the same Podrick?
给提利昂大人当侍从的那个闷小子？
The quiet boy in Lord Tyrion's service?
看上去很天真的那个？
Seems a bit simple?
他对她们做了什么？
What did he do to them?
这我可不知道 大人
I don't know, my lord.
这群姑娘们通常很会夸夸其谈的不是么
The girls are usually quite descriptive.
她们怎么说的？
So what did they say?
她们说这回不太好解释
They said it was hard to describe.
这
Huh.
人才出现在了最古怪的地方
Prodigies appear in the oddest of places.
那小指头呢？对他的损失有什么反应？
And what did Littlefinger say about this loss of income?
他太忙了 才没空管这些
He was too preoccupied to notice.
他即将动身去鹰巢城了
He's leaving for the Eyrie soon.
我在帮他打点行装
I'm helping him prepare for his journey.
啊是啊 去追求他与艾林夫人不朽的爱情
Ah, yes, to pursue his enduring love
还有那随她而来的名号
of the Lady Arryn and the title that comes with her.
真是可悲
Sad, really.
这就让我们的朋友
Is that all it takes
对可怜的珊莎・史塔克失去兴趣了么？
to make our friend lose interest in poor Sansa Stark?
自从上次之后他就没和她再交谈过了
He hasn't spoken to her since the last time,
至少据我所知如此
as far as I know.
我倒不认为他失去兴趣了
But I don't think he's lost interest.
你怎么知道
What makes you say so?
- 他的登船清单 - 噢
- His shipboard inventory. - Ah.
你认字
You can read.
干咱们这行的姑娘中这还真少见
Rare for a woman in your profession.
- 老本行 - 当然
- Former profession. - Of course.
对了我们还是回归正题吧 你刚才想说什么来着？
I'm missing something obvious you're about to point out?
两张羽毛床
Two featherbeds.
他要把两张羽毛床搬到床上
He's bringing two featherbeds for the cabin.
除了小指头自己 还能有谁这么重要
Who is important enough to Littlefinger
得劳驾小指头带上羽毛床？
to merit a featherbed besides Littlefinger?
可能他带着他的一个姑娘？
Could he be bringing one of his girls?
他对她们可没兴趣 大人
He's not interested in them, my lord.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
因为我就是她们中的一个
Because I'm one of his girls.
真是怪处出人才
Prodigies in odd places indeed.
雷妮拉・坦格利安是被她弟弟所谋害的
Rhaenyra Targaryen was murdered by her brother,
或者说是她弟弟的龙
or rather his dragon.
这野兽在她儿子面前吃了她
It ate her while her son watched.
这下面地穴里埋着的 是她被吃剩的残尸
What's left of her is buried in the crypts right down there.
遵照传统婚礼将会在大圣堂里举行
The ceremony is traditionally held in the main sanctum,
那里摆得下700个座位
which seats 700 comfortably.
看起来应该在厅里再安排些席位
There appears to be a good deal of room elsewhere
以接纳其它的来客
on the premises for everyone else.
可我们要宴请的贵宾只有700个啊
There aren't more than 700 people of any importance.
的确 剩下的都是来捧人场的
No, the rest are there to look adoringly
让那700个人意识到自己
upon the 700 to remind them
是有多么的荣幸才能位列贵席
how superior they must be to have the best seats.
在那个瓮里的是
Over there in that urn,
瑟曦・兰尼斯特
摄政太后
奥莲娜夫人
玛格丽・提利尔的祖母
伊里昂・坦格利安的骨灰
the ashes of Aerion Targaryen.
人称“明焰”伊里昂
Aerion Brightflame they called him.
玛格丽・提利尔
乔佛里国王的未婚妻
乔佛里・拜拉席恩
铁王座上的王
他相信喝下野火就能变成真龙
He thought drinking wildfire would turn him into a dragon.
显然他错了
He was wrong.
当然 那儿还有疯王
And, of course, there's the Mad King,
我舅舅杀死的那个
killed by my uncle.
你想看看最后的坦格利安被埋在哪里吗？
Would you like to see where the last Targaryens are buried?
你确定玛格丽小姐不会觉得这有点恐怖吗？
Are you sure Lady Margaery doesn't find all this a bit macabre?
哦 不会 没有什么的 陛下
Oh, no, it's quite all right, Your Grace.
我很想看看他们的墓穴
I'd love to see their tombs, really.
就像是在历史中漫步一样
It's like taking a walk through history.
- 墓穴就在那里 C真是让人激动
- The tomb's just up here. - This is so exciting.
您是在这里成婚的么 陛下？
You were married here, Your Grace?
- 是的 - 一定就像是昨天一样
- Yes. - Must seem like only yesterday.
就像是上辈子的事情
Seems like a lifetime ago.
您的亡夫 也埋葬在这里吗？
Your husband, was he buried here as well?
不 他希望将遗骨葬在风息堡
No, he wanted his remains returned to Storm's End.
- 真是个悲剧 - 一个显而易见的悲剧
- Such a tragedy. - A fairly predictable tragedy.
打猎的时候怎么能够酗酒
Hunting and drinking don't mix.
可不是嘛
I should say not.
我儿子是个猎人 这总是让他忘记
My son's a hunter. It helps him forget
自己从未接近过真刀真枪的战争
he's never been within a mile of a real battle.
可我记得他曾经围攻过风息堡
I seem to recall he laid siege to Storm's End
围城了大半年了
for the better part of a year.
他围攻的
All he laid siege to
不过是他大帐里的宴席而已
was the banquet table in the command tent.
我警告过他别参与劳勃的叛乱
I told him to stay out of Robert's rebellion.
他根本没那个实力 去和真正的战士较量
He had no business fighting an actual warrior.
我们这些母亲总是极尽所能地
We mothers do what we can
让自己的儿子远离死亡
to keep our sons from the grave.
不过他们却为之乐此不疲
But they do seem to yearn for it.
我们灌输给他们的理智
We shower them with good sense,
像羽翼上的雨滴一样潸然流走
and it slides right off like rain off a wing.
可现实是 这世道是属于他们的
And yet the world belongs to them.
真是个荒唐的安排啊
A ridiculous arrangement, to my mind.
也许七神认为这是合适的安排吧
The gods have seen fit to make it so.
我父亲不希望他们留在这里
My father didn't want them here.
他要烧了他们的遗体
He was going to have their bodies burned
然后丢进黑水河去
and thrown in the Blackwater,
不过大主教让他改了主意
but the High Septon convinced him otherwise.
我很高兴他这么做了
I'm glad he did.
很抱歉 陛下
I'm sorry, Your Grace.
我明白他们最后做了很糟糕的事
I know they did terrible things at the end,
但是他们的祖先建造了这个城堡
but their ancestors built this.
有的时候疯狂
Sometimes severity
是换取伟大的代价
is the price we pay for greatness.
感同身受
I couldn't agree more.
我们要去看他们吗？
Shall we go and see them?
如果你给予他们爱
If you give them your love,
他们会千万倍的奉还
they will return it a thousandfold.
我和他们交谈过
I've spoken with them.
我知道他们怎么看待你
I know how they feel about you.
你领导了君临的防御战
You led the defense of King's Landing.
他们崇拜你
They adore you.
把门打开
Open the doors.
乔佛里
Joffrey.
等一下
Wait.
- 玛格丽小姐！ - 玛格丽小姐！
- Lady Margaery! - Lady Margaery!
祝福你 玛格丽小姐！
Bless you, Lady Margaery!
- 玛格丽小姐！ - 玛格丽小姐！
- Lady Margaery! - Lady Margaery!
- 玛格丽！ - 玛格丽小姐万岁！
- Margaery! - Long live Lady Margaery!
乔佛里国王！
King Joffrey!
乔佛里国王！乔佛里国王！
King Joffrey! King Joffrey!
乔佛里国王！
King Joffrey!
七神祝福乔佛里国王！
Gods bless King Joffrey!
离深林堡还有多远？
How far is it to Deepwood Motte?
不远了 大人
Not far, my lord.
你的姐姐在那等你
Your sister is waiting for you there.
- 她派你来救我的？ - 没错
- She sent you to save me? - Yes.
我曾为那些折磨你的人效命
I served them, the men who were torturing you.
我照他们说的去做 直到时机成熟
I did what they told me and waited for the right moment.
你为什么要为我冒险？
Why would you risk your life for me?
席恩・葛雷乔伊
铁群岛继承人
我是在盐崖岛长大的 大人
I grew up on Saltcliffe, my lord.
他们把你带走的时候我还是个小孩
I was only a boy when they took you away.
我的父亲把我和我的兄弟们带到断崖上
My father brought me and my brothers up to the bluffs
我们目送载着你的船离去
so we could watch the ship that carried you off.
我还记得我父亲的神情 当他说
I remember the look on my father's face when he told us,
“这是巴隆・葛雷乔伊唯一活着的儿子”
"That's Balon Greyjoy's last living son."
当我看到他们折磨你的时候
And those are the words I heard over and over again
这些话就在我的脑中回响个不停
when I saw what they were doing to you.
那些人
Those men,
他们说我父亲知道他们对我做什么
they said my father knew what they were doing to me.
是真的吗？
Did he?
我…… 我不知道 大人
I-- I don't know, my lord.
他们…… 他们从来不会告诉我很多
They-- they never told me much.
我姐姐的人都很忠诚
My sister's men are loyal to her.
我不需要躲躲藏藏的
We don't need to hide from them.
可并不是所有的人都是你姐姐的部下
Not all those are your sister's men.
还有些人是忠于你父亲的
Some of them are loyal to your father.
这是做什么？
What is it?
只是在想那时我是如何被妒火吞没的
I was just thinking how jealous I was
当我听到父亲命令雅拉攻打这里的时候
when my father told Yara to take this place.
他给你安排了什么任务？
What did he tell you to do?
去掠夺渔村
Raid fishing villages.
他不信任我
He didn't trust me.
他认为我是个史塔克
Thought I was a Stark.
呵呵 我永远都不会成为史塔克
Ha. I could never be a Stark.
罗柏・史塔克总是提醒我这点
Robb Stark always reminded me of that.
- 他曾经凌驾于你之上么？ - 他没这个必要
- He lorded it over you? - Didn't have to.
他只需顺其自然就够了
All he had to do was be.
他生来就高人一等
Be who he was born to be.
他的人生是如此的一帆风顺
His life fit him better than his clothes.
像他这样的人 又怎么会拿我当兄弟呢？
How could someone like that ever be a brother to me?
他可是北境之王
He's the King in the North.
而我……
And me...
我父亲给了我一个选择
my father gave me a choice
我也做出了决定
and I made it.
我不可能成为一个史塔克
I could never be a Stark.
我是个铁种
But ironborn,
这才是我生来的命运
that's what I was born to be.
我付铁钱换来了临冬城
I paid the iron price for Winterfell.
我谋杀了那两个男孩
I murdered those boys.
史塔克家的男孩？
The Stark boys?
我就没找到过他们
Never found them.
我杀的不过是农夫家养的可怜孤儿
Just some poor orphans living with a farmer.
我让达格摩割了他们的喉咙
I let Dagmer slit their throats
然后让他们烧掉尸体
and I let him burn the bodies...
这样我就能占有临冬城
so I could keep Winterfell...
让我父亲骄傲
and make my father proud.
也许还不算太晚
Maybe it's not too late.
已经太晚了
It is.
我真正的父亲在君临掉了脑袋
My real father lost his head at King's Landing.
而我 已经做过了选择……
I made a choice...
一个错误的选择
and I chose wrong.
现在我把一切都搞砸了
And now I've burned everything down.
不是一切 大人
Not everything, my lord.
她来了
She's up here.
- 雅拉 - 嘘
- Yara. - Shh.
等着
Wait.
我带他回来了 他杀了其他人
I brought him back. He killed the others.
什么？我没有
What? No, I didn't.
你不能！
You can't!
不 停下！
No, please stop!
不！
No!
把他扔回属于他的地方去
Put him back where he belongs.
吃吧
Eat.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我要死了
I'm dying.
你不能
You can't die.
你得活下去
You need to live
活下去复仇
to take revenge.
我才不管什么复仇了
I don't care about revenge.
你个懦夫
You coward.
不过是这么一点不如意 你就放弃了
A little misfortune and you're giving up.
不如……
mis-
不如意？
misfortune?
我失去了我的手
You lost your hand.
那是我用剑的手 我就是那只手
My sword hand. I was that hand.
你终于尝到了――
You have a taste--
真实世界的滋味
one taste of the real world
一旦被夺走了重要的事物
where people have important things taken from them
就哭天喊地 心灰意冷
and you whine and cry and quit.
你听起来像个娘们
You sound like a bloody woman.
我知道你为我做了什么
I know what you did for me.
你跟他们说塔斯全是蓝宝石
You told them Tarth was full of sapphires.
塔斯之所以被称为蓝宝石岛
It's called the Sapphire Isle
是因为那里蔚蓝的海水
because of the blue of its water.
你是知道的
You knew that.
你为什么要帮我？
Why did you help me?
泰温・兰尼斯特
凯岩城公爵 国王之手
你找我？
You wanted to speak to me?
对 关于詹姆
Yes, about Jaime.
他怎么了？
What about him?
我想确保
I wanted to make sure
我们会尽全力让他回来
we're doing everything we can to get him back.
凯特琳・史塔克当初抓走提利昂……
When Catelyn Stark took Tyrion prisoner...
我是怎么回应的？
what did I do in response?
- 您发动了一场战争  - 既然我会
- You started a war. - And if I would start a war
为了那个好色的小残废发动一场战争
for that lecherous little stump,
为了我的长子和继承人 你说我会怎么做？
what do you think I am doing for my oldest son and heir?
尽您所能
Whatever you can.
尽我所能
Whatever I can.
- 还不走啊 - 对
- You're still here. - Yes.
为什么？
Why?
您有没有想过
Did it ever occur to you
也许我是最值得您信任的人
that I might be the one who deserves your confidence
而不是您的儿子们？
and your trust, not your sons?
不是詹姆也不是提利昂 是我
Not Jaime or Tyrion, but me.
年复一年的教诲
Years and years of lectures on family
有关家族和祖传家业
and legacy--
千篇一律
the same lecture, really,
只有乏味而微小的改变
just with tiny, tedious variations--
不知您是否意识到您的女儿
did it ever occur to you that your daughter
可能是唯一把教诲听进去的人？
might be the only one listening to them?
可能是唯一以此为信念的人
Living by them?
您把祖训看得比自己的孩子们要重要得多
That she might have the most to contribute to your legacy
而她也许最能帮助您去完成
that you love so much more than your actual children?
好吧 来帮助我
All right. Contribute.
提利尔家族是个问题
The Tyrells are a problem.
提利尔家族帮我们打败了史坦尼斯・拜拉席恩
The Tyrells helped us defeat Stannis Baratheon.
提利尔家族救了你的命 救了你孩子们的命
The Tyrells saved your life, your children's lives.
玛格丽将魔爪伸向了乔佛里
Margaery has her claws in Joffrey.
她懂得如何操控他
She knows how to manipulate him.
很好
Good.
我真希望你也懂得如何操控他
I wish you knew how to manipulate him.
我不信任你 不是因为你是女人
I don't distrust you because you're a woman.
而是因为你自以为是
I distrust you because you're not as smart as you think you are.
你让儿子骑在你头上
You've allowed that boy to ride roughshod over you
还任凭他欺压城里的所有人
and everyone else in this city.
也许......
Perhaps...
您应该阻止他为所欲为
you should try stopping him from doing what he likes.
我会的
I will.
您喜欢吗 奶奶？
Do you like it, Nana?
又一朵金玫瑰 真没劲
Another golden rose. How original.
我吃饭的盘子里刻着玫瑰
I eat from plates stamped with roses.
我睡觉的被单上绣着玫瑰
I sleep in sheets embroidered with roses.
我的夜壶上画着金玫瑰
I have a golden rose painted on my chamber pot,
难道这样就能好闻点
as if that makes it smell any better.
亲爱的 玫瑰很无趣
Roses are boring, dear.
“生生不息”
"Growing strong."
所有家族中最无趣的族语
Ha! The dullest words of any house.
“凛冬将至！”
"Winter is coming!"
这才让人过目不忘
Now that's memorable.
“强取胜于苦耕”多么强大
"We do not sow." Strong. Strong.
这些才是你会防备的家族
Those are houses you watch out for.
冰原狼 海怪 凶猛的野兽
Direwolves and krakens, fierce beasts.
但生生不息的金玫瑰――
But a golden rose growing strong--
哈 真让人心惊胆战
ha, that strikes fear in the heart.
瞧 小可爱们
Look, little loves.
花园里来了只蜘蛛
A spider in the garden.
去吧
Run along now.
生生不息
Grow strong.
夫人
My lady.
我想亲自欢迎您来到君临
I wanted to personally welcome you to King's Landing.
城市因您的到来而熠熠生辉
The city has been made brighter by your presence.
城市因我的到来而熠熠生辉？
The city is made brighter by my presence?
这是你的常用台词吗 瓦里斯大人？
Is that your usual line, Lord Varys?
你是来找我搭讪的吗？
Are you here to seduce me?
也许是有点明显了
A little obvious, perhaps.
哦不 请便
Oh, no, please.
都这么久了 请继续吧
Seduce away. It's been so long.
但我觉得你这是白费力气
Though I rather think it's all for naught.
一个缺东西的和一个老太婆能发生什么？
What happens when the nonexistent bumps against the decrepit?
这个问题留给哲学家吧
A question for the philosophers.
可你绕了这么久的弯子 究竟为了什么而来？
But you've come mincing all this way for something.
- 说吧？ - 我能坐下吗？
- So? - Might I sit?
不行
No.
说吧 我听说你是个聪明人
Come, I've heard you're such a clever man.
我很好奇你为什么来找我
I'm curious why you've sought me out.
您对珊莎・史塔克很有兴趣
You've taken an interest in Sansa Stark.
是吗？
Have I?
就因为我和她在这花园里聊过一次
Because I spoke to her once in this garden
你的探子就跑去报告了？
and one of your little spies came running to tell you?
我为什么不能感兴趣？
Why shouldn't I take an interest?
- 她是个引人注意的女孩 - 是吗？
- She's an interesting girl. - Is she?
不 并没什么特别之处
No, not particularly.
不过她的童年倒是让人颇感兴趣
But she's had an interesting childhood.
是啊 悲惨的童年
She has, sadly.
请原谅 浪费了您的时间
Well, forgive me for wasting your time, then.
我原以为我们都对她的幸福心怀关切
I thought we shared certain hopes for her well-being.
得了吧
Come, come.
你不能这么快就缴械投降了
You surrender rather easily.
和我走一走
Walk with me.
我知道隔墙有耳
I know the walls have ears,
但很显然 灌木丛中也有
but apparently the shrubbery does, too.
我挑选同盟很小心
I choose my allies carefully
挑选敌人则会更加小心
and my enemies more carefully still.
珊莎是同盟还是敌人？
Which is Sansa Stark?
都不是 涉世未深的小孩
Neither. A babe in the woods.
- 我景仰她的父亲 - 的确
- I admired her father. - Yes.
奈德・史塔克有很多景仰者
Ned Stark had many admirers,
又有多少人挺身而出
and how many stepped forward
阻止刽子手砍去他的头颅？
when the executioner came for his head?
我帮不了史塔克大人
I could not help Lord Stark.
- 也许我能帮到他的女儿 - 怎么帮？
- Perhaps I can help his daughter. - How?
您不是唯一对她感兴趣的人
You're not the only one who has taken an interest in her.
这不奇怪
That's hardly surprising.
她是个美丽的姑娘 家族显赫
She's a beautiful girl with a famous name.
的确 如果有合适的求婚者 她会是个不错的妻子
Indeed. She'd make a lovely match for the right suitor.
我感觉您快说到关键点了
It almost feels as if you're about to arrive at the point.
小指头不会在君临久留
Littlefinger is not long for the capital.
我的一个心腹朋友告诉我
A confidant of mine has told me
小指头走的时候 会带珊莎・史塔克一起走
that when he goes, Sansa Stark goes with him.
为什么您要来告诉我这件事？
And why have you come to me with this matter?
小指头生来没有封地 没有财产也没有军队
Littlefinger was born with no lands, no wealth, no armies.
现在他已经买到了头两样
He has acquired the first two.
还需要多久他就能拥有军队？
How long before he has the army?
也许您会笑我
Perhaps you'll laugh,
但我比大多数人都更了解他
but I know him better than most
这是事实
and this is the truth.
小指头是维斯特洛最危险的人之一
Littlefinger is one of the most dangerous men in Westeros.
如果罗柏・史塔克失势
If Robb Stark falls,
珊莎・史塔克就是北境的钥匙
Sansa Stark is the key to the North.
如果小指头娶了她 就等于拿到了这把钥匙
And if Littlefinger marries her, he'll have the key in his pocket.
这可真是让人羞愧
Which seems such a shame.
一个声誉如此之差的人怎么能
Why should a man with such a low reputation
抢走这样一位美丽的新娘？
steal away such a lovely bride?
你一定很瞧不起他
You must despise him.
才费了这么多口舌来贬低他
You're working so hard to undermine him.
实际上 我很欣赏他
Actually, I rather enjoy him.
可是 只要能当上哪怕一个灰烬之王
But he would see this country burn
他甚至不惜坐视整个王国被付之一炬
if he could be king of the ashes.
你是个聪明人 瓦里斯大人
You are a clever man, Lord Varys.
您过奖了
You are too kind.
我倒是有个可行的方案
I believe I have a possible solution.
用不着像你这么聪明也能想到
One doesn't need to be clever for that.
这都明摆着 不是吗？
It's all rather obvious, isn't it?
咳咳
Ahem.
我不是故意打扰你的
I didn't mean to disturb you.
珊莎・史塔克
你没有打扰
You haven't.
不介意的话 请到城堡里等着
We'd like some privacy, please.
我们想私下里谈谈
If you wouldn't mind waiting back inside the keep.
或者告诉我你们的名字
Or if you'd be kind enough to give me your names,
我会让国王亲自来跟你们说
I'll ask the king to speak with you himself.
你在祈祷什么？
What did you pray for?
- 我不能告诉你 - 为什么？
- I can't tell you. - Why not?
我来告诉你今早我在圣堂祈祷了什么
I'll tell you what I prayed for in the sept this morning.
我想想 我祈祷我的家族幸福安康
Let's see, for my family's health and happiness,
战争划上句点 冬天早日结束
for an end to the war, for a short winter.
恐怕很无聊 很老套
Boring and traditional, I'm afraid.
- 你呢？ - 抱歉 我不能说
- And you? - I'm sorry, I just can't.
我的表姐阿莱娜
My cousin Alanna
是我见过最美的女孩
was the most beautiful girl I'd ever seen.
我12岁时 经常摔得青一块紫一块
When I was 12, I was all elbows and knees
阿莱娜就像是上天派来折磨我的女神
and Alanna looked like a goddess sent to torture me.
她叫我猪脸
Pig-face, she called me.
猪脸？这真荒唐
Pig-face? That's ridiculous.
我想是因为我的鼻子
I think it had something to do with my nose.
她只要在大厅里见到我 就会学猪叫
Whenever she passed me in the halls, she'd oink.
所以我祈祷她会染上可怕的皮肤病
So I prayed that she'd catch a horrible skin disease.
一周后 她得了粥斑病
A week after that, she came down with porridge plague.
- 粥斑病？ - 你们北境没有吗？
- Porridge plague? - You don't have it in the North?
皮肤开始时像煮开了的燕麦片
Your skin starts to look like boiled oats
最后脸部脱落 在痛苦中死去
and eventually your face slides off and you diein agony.
这太可怕了
But that's awful.
你――
You're--
我居然相信了你！
I believed you!
粥斑病 我是个白痴
Porridge plague. I'm an idiot.
你不是的 别这么说
Don't say that. No, you're not.
阿莱娜后来怎样了？
So what happened to Alanna?
她长大后成为最美丽的女子
Oh, she grew up to be the most beautiful woman
嫁给了一位英俊的大人 有了心爱的孩子们
and married a handsome lord and they have darling children
住在海边的城堡里
and live in a castle by the sea.
真让人沮丧
It's all terribly frustrating.
她现在一定很嫉妒你
I'm sure she's jealous of you now.
你嫁到君临来
You'll be married here in the capital
她会来看你 为你成为王后而假装高兴
and she'll have to come watch and pretend to be happy that you're queen.
我希望和你成为朋友 好朋友
I want us to be friends, good friends.
我会非常高兴的
That would make me very happy.
你一定要到高庭来
You must see Highgarden.
你会喜欢那儿的 我知道你一定会的
You'd love it there. I know you would.
我们会在丰收月晚上举行盛大的化妆舞会
We have a great masquerade the night of the harvest moon.
你一定要来看看戏服
You should see the costumes.
人们制作了好几个月
People work on them for months.
我――我不认为王后
I-- I don't think the queen
会允许我离开君临
would let me leave King's Landing.
你是指摄政太后吧
The Queen Regent, you mean.
等我嫁给乔佛里 我就会成为王后
Once I marry Joffrey, I'll be queen.
然后 如果你嫁给洛拉斯……
And if you were to marry Loras...
你就会呆在高庭 不是吗？
Oh, your place would be at Highgarden, wouldn't it?
我们就是姐妹了
We would be sisters, you and I.
你喜欢这提议吗？
Would you like that?
他叫巴棱
His name was Bannen.
杰奥・莫尔蒙
“熊老” 守夜人总司令
他是个好人
He was a good man,
优秀的游骑兵
a good ranger.
他来自……
He came to us from--
他是哪儿人？
where did he come from?
白港
Down White Harbor way.
他从白港来到我们中间
He came to us from White Harbor.
恪尽职守
Never failed in his duty.
全力谨遵誓言
He kept his vows the best he could.
他一马当前 奋勇作战
He rode far, fought fiercely.
我们将难得再见如此之人
We shall never see his like again.
他的守望至死方休 于斯结束
And now his watch has ended.
没想到区区脚伤也会要了他的命
Didn't think a broke foot could kill a man.
脚伤可弄不死他
It wasn't his foot that killed him.
是卡斯特那杂种把他给活活饿死了
That bastard Craster starved him to death.
卡斯特得养自己的女儿
Craster's got his daughters to feed.
你还帮他说话？
You on his side?
我们不能打个招呼 就把他的食物偷走
We can't just show up and steal all his food.
我们是守夜人 不是贼
We're brothers of the Night's Watch, not thieves.
我们离开那天
The day we leave,
卡斯特肯定会开一瓶好酒
Craster will tap a barrel of our wine
摆上一桌火腿土豆筵席大吃一顿
and sit down to a feast of ham and potatoes
然后嘲笑我们
and laugh at us
在冰天雪地里挨饿受冻
starving in the snow.
他是个该死的野人
He's a bloody wildling is all he is.
我没想到巴棱也能烤得这么香
Never knew Bannen could smell so good.
卡斯特
野人
莫尔蒙 你有个儿子吧
You have one son, don't you, Mormont?
我有99个儿子
I had my 99th.
你还没见过哪个老子有99个儿子吧？
You ever meet a man with 99 sons?
我女儿多得数不过来
And more daughters than I can count.
我真为你高兴 呵呵 真的？
- I'm glad for you. - Are you now?
我可希望你和你的崽子们早点滚蛋
Me, I'll be glad when you and yours have gone.
等伤兵再恢复些我们就离开
As soon as our wounded are strong enough.
唉
Ah.
他们这样已经算不错了
They're as strong as they're gonna get.
那些只剩一口气的
Them that's dying,
怎么不直接给喉咙上开道口子了结算了？
why don't you cut their throats and be done with it?
啊？
Hmm?
如果你不想的话 可以留给我
Or leave them if you've not the stomach
我来帮你代劳
and I'll sort them myself.
你要了结了谁啊 老头子？
Whose throat you gonna cut, old man?
给我出去等着
Wait outside.
外边太冷了 一丁点吃的都没有
It's cold outside and there's nothing to eat.
我老婆给过你们面包了
My wives gave you bread.
面包里满是木屑
There's sawdust in the bread.
如果你不喜欢
You don't like it,
你可以出去找点雪吃
you go out there and eat the snow.
我只想吃你藏起来的好东西
I'd rather eat what you've got hidden away.
我说了 出去等着
I told you to wait outside.
他现在坐在这儿喝我们的酒
He's sitting there drinking our wine,
得等我们死了才会享用他屯的好东西
eating his fill while we die.
我已经给你们这些乌鸦够多了
I gave you crows enough.
我得喂饱我的女人们！
I've got to feed my women!
你这是承认自己把好东西都藏起来了？
So you admit you've got a hidden larder, then?
否则你怎么过冬？
How else'd you make it through winter?
够了！滚出去！
Enough! Out!
我可是个敬神的人
I am a godly man.
你是个吝啬的杂种！
You're a stingy bastard!
杂种？
Bastard?
我跟你这小贼出去说话！
Out with you, you little thief.
还有你！和你！
And you! And you!
都给我滚到雪地里饿肚子去
Go sleep in the cold on empty bellies.
谁再敢说我是杂种
I'll chop the hands off the next man
我就把他的手砍下来
who calls me bastard.
你就是个杂种
You are a bastard.
操女儿的野人 该死的杂种
A daughter-fucking, wildling bastard.
诸神会为此诅咒我们的
The gods will curse us for this.
诸神的律法将――
By all the laws--
长城之外 没有律法
There are no laws beyond the Wall.
告诉我们他把那些好东西都藏在哪儿了
Now show us where he hides the food
否则你的下场就和他一样
or you'll get the same as he did.
放开她
Unhand her.
我要砍了你的头
I shall have your head for this.
- 赶紧 赶紧 - 发生了什么？
- Quickly. Quickly. - What's happening?
- 我可不敢出去 - 不 我们必须逃跑 快逃！
- I'm not going out there. - No, we have to go. Now!
跟我来 我知道小路捷径
Follow me. I know the best way.
走这边
Come on.
猪崽儿 跑快点
Run fast, Piggy,
睡好！
and sleep well!
到时候我就来解决你
I'll be cutting your throat one of these nights.
能帮我把这头罩摘下来了吗？
Can I take this hood off yet?
我很抱歉 小姐
I do apologize, little lady,
但你还是不知道我们去哪儿的好
but it's better for you if you don't see where we're going.
停下！
Halt!
- 这是什么？ - 黑带朗姆酒
- What is it? - Blackstrap rum.
密尔的索罗斯
无旗兄弟会的红袍僧
啊！
Ugh!
要在战争时期找点安慰可不容易
Not easy finding molasses in wartime.
我也来点
I'd have some.
安盖
“射手” 来自风暴地的弓箭手
我们回家了
Let's go home.
这是哪儿？
What is this place?
狼和狮子都找不到的地方
Somewhere neither wolves nor lions come prowling.
艾莉亚・史塔克
詹德利
“大牛” 铁匠学徒
桑铎・克里冈
“猎狗”
你们看着就像群猪倌
You look like a bunch of swineherds.
我们中的确有些猪倌
Some of us were swineherds.
还有些皮革工和石匠
And some of us tanners and masons.
那都是过去的事了
That was before.
你们仍旧是猪倌
You're still swineherds
皮革工和石匠
and tanners and masons.
拿把破矛就能当战士了？
You think carrying a crooked spear makes you a soldier?
不
No.
战争才能铸就真正的战士
Fighting in a war makes you a soldier.
贝里・唐德利恩？
Beric Dondarrion?
你有过好日子 如今落到这般田地
You've seen better days.
贝里・唐德利恩
“闪电大王” 无旗兄弟会的领袖
好日子一去不复返了
And I won't see them again.
史塔克的逃兵
Stark deserters.
拜拉席恩的逃兵
Baratheon deserters.
你们才不是参加战争
You lot aren't fighting in a war.
你们是战场的逃兵
You're running from it.
我上次听到你的消息 你还是乔佛里国王的忠狗
Last I heard, you were King Joffrey's guard dog.
可你如今千里迢迢赶到这儿
But here you are 1,000 miles from home.
咱俩谁是逃兵呢？
Which of us is running?
解开绳子我们就知道了
Untie these ropes and we'll find out.
你躲这儿带着帮农民想做什么？
What are you doing leading a mob of peasants?
奈德・史塔克让我杀了你兄弟
Ned Stark ordered me to execute your brother
以劳勃国王之名
in King Robert's name.
奈德・史塔克早死了
Ned Stark is dead.
劳勃国王也躺在坟墓里头
King Robert is dead.
我兄弟可还活得好好的
My brother's alive.
你们这是为了死人而战
You're fighting for ghosts.
我们就是孤魂野鬼――
That's what we are--
在黑暗中等待你大驾光临
ghosts waiting for you in the dark.
你看不见我们
You can't see us,
但我们能看见你
but we see you.
无论你身穿哪家战袍――
No matter whose cloak you wear--
兰尼斯特 史塔克 拜拉席恩――
Lannister, Stark, Baratheon--
你要是对弱者下手
you prey on the weak,
无旗兄弟会便会将你拿下
the Brotherhood without Banners will hunt you down.
你找到了神？当真？
You found god? Is that it?
没错 我在世间唯一真神的光里
Aye. I've been reborn
获得了重生
in the light of the one true god.
我们都是如此
As have we all.
世间有此经历的人都会如此
As would any man who's seen the things we've seen.
如果你想杀了我 他妈的赶紧动手
If you mean to murder me, then bloody well get on with it.
你迟早会死 狗
You'll die soon enough, dog.
非为谋杀 只为正义
But it won't be murder, only justice.
这比你应得的要慷慨多了
And a kinder fate than you deserve.
你们总自称是狮子
Lions you call yourselves.
戏子滩上 你们强奸了七岁的小女孩
At the Mummer's Ford, girls of seven years were raped
喂奶的母亲
and babes still on the breast
眼睁睁地看着自己的儿女被切成两半
were cut in two while their mothers watched.
我那时不在戏子滩
I wasn't at the Mummer's Ford.
别把这笔烂帐算到我头上
Dump your dead children at some other door.
克里冈家族就是构筑在死婴之上的
House Clegane was built upon dead children.
我亲眼目睹他们将伊耿王子和雷妮丝公主的尸体
I saw them lay Prince Aegon and Princess Rhaenys
陈放在铁王座前
before the Iron Throne.
你以为我跟我老哥一样？
Do you take me for my brother?
生于克里冈家就是罪名？
Is being born Clegane a crime?
- 谋杀是罪名 - 我可没碰过坦格利安的崽子们
- Murder is a crime. - I never touched the Targaryen babes.
从没见过 连闻都没闻过
I never saw them, never smelled them,
连他们的哭啼声都没听过
never heard them bawling.
你想杀了我 那就赶紧来！
You want to cut my throat, get on with it!
别把杀人者的名头扣在我头上
But don't call me murderer
然后自己假装不是
and pretend that you're not.
你杀了米凯
You murdered Mycah.
屠夫家的儿子
The butcher's boy.
我的好朋友
My friend.
他才12岁 手无寸铁
He was 12 years old. He was unarmed.
你骑马追杀他
And you rode him down.
你把他的尸体挂在马背上 就像是你猎杀的一头鹿
You slung him over your horse like he was some deer.
唉 我才碰碰他就往外冒血
Aye, he was a bleeder.
你并不否认你杀了那个孩子？
You don't deny killing this boy?
我是乔佛里的贴身侍卫
I was Joffrey's sworn shield.
- 那孩子袭击王子 - 你说谎！
- The boy attacked the prince. - That's a lie!
是我打伤了乔佛里 米凯逃走了
I hit Joffrey. Mycah just ran away.
那我应该杀了你
Then I should have killed you.
我没资格质疑王子
Not my place to question princes.
你被控谋杀
You stand accused of murder.
但此处没人知道指控的真假
But no one here knows the truth of the charge,
所以我们无法裁定
so it is not for us to judge you.
只有光之王才能审判你
Only the Lord of Light may do that now.
我决定进行比武审判
I sentence you to trial by combat.
那么 你们谁上呢？
So, who will it be?
我们来看看你的火神究竟
Should we find out if your fire god
爱不爱你 牧师先生？
really loves you, priest?
或者是你 弓箭手？
Or you, archer?
我很想见识一下你的剑法哟？
What are you worth with a sword in your hand?
还是我们最勇敢的小丫头呢？
Or is the little girl the bravest one here?
对
Aye.
她的确勇敢
She might be.
但你的对手是我
But it's me you'll fight.
丹妮莉丝・坦格利安
风暴降生 龙之母
克拉兹尼・莫・纳克罗兹
阿斯塔波的奴隶主
格雷赞
主人说他们还未经考验
The master says they are untested.
他说最好先让他们接受血的试练
He says you would be wise to blood them early.
这儿周边有许多小城市
There are many small cities between here and there,
这些城市有丰富的资源
cities ripe for sacking.
如果你抓到了俘虏
Should you take captives,
贤主们可以高价收购健康的战俘
the masters will buy the healthy ones and for a good price.
世事难料
And who knows?
10年后你送来的某些男孩子
In 10 years, some of the boys you send them
也许也会成为无垢者
may be Unsullied in their turn.
弥桑黛
奴隶翻译
这对我们都有利
Thus all shall prosper.
乔拉・莫尔蒙
“大熊” 熊老之子
巴利斯坦・赛尔弥
“无畏的” 女王铁卫
卓耿
丹妮莉丝的黑龙
成交了吗？他们属于我了？
Is it done, then? They belong to me?
成交了
你握紧这鞭子
这支军队归你这婊子了
无垢者！
向前进！
立定！
这婊子的怪物不听我话啊
龙可不是奴隶
你会说瓦雷利亚语？
吾乃坦格利安家族的风暴降生丹妮莉丝
吾乃旧瓦雷利亚后裔
瓦雷利亚语是我的母语
无垢者！
杀死奴隶主！
杀死这些士兵！杀死每一位手握鞭子的人！
但不要伤害孩子！
斩断每一位奴隶的锁链！
我才是你们的主人！
杀了她！杀了她！
杀了她！
龙焰
Dracarys.
无垢者！
你们生为奴隶 从今日起你们都是自由之身！
你们可以自由离开 没人会伤害你们！
我在此立誓！
你们愿意为我而战吗？以自由之身？
衣柜字幕组出品